Fatma Usta

+1 (848) 213-2196 / ustafatma91@gmail.com Eligible to work in Canada

GitHub: fatmausta / LinkedIn: fatmausta

INTRO:

I am currently developing deep learning algorithms with Siemens Healthineers in the USA. I earned my Master's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering in Canada in 2018. I have 2-year hands-on experience with Python.

I am a native speaker of Turkish, and very fluent in English.

PROFICIENCY:

Python | PyTorch | Keras | Tensorflow | Matlab | C++ | CUDA

EXPERIENCE:

Deep Learning Developer Mar 2018-Current

Siemens Healthineers, Princeton, New Jersey, USA

- ❖ Hands-on experience with deep learning in Python using PyTorch, Keras and (native) Tensorflow.
- ❖ Practical experience in time-series data for calcified plaque detection using CNN+LSTM models.
- Working experience in training with large datasets on high-speed GPU Clusters in Linux Environment.
- Experience working in collaboration with deep learning research teams.

Teaching Assistantship Sep 2017-Dec 2017

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

- ❖ Taught and guided over 200 undergraduate students during laboratory sessions for the course "Introduction to Software Engineering".
- * Taught Git/GitHub, Java, NoSQL, and Android App Development with Firebase Database.

Web-Developer and Database Manager

Sep 2012-Jun 2013

Kirikkale University Research and Training Hospital, Kirikkale, Turkey

(1-Year Part-time)

- * Redesigned the hospital website using PHP, HTML, and SQL on Oracle database.
- Strengthen the encryption algorithm to encounter the frequent injection attacks to the database.

Software Engineer Summer Intern

Jul-Aug 2012

JeoIT, Microsoft Partner Company, Ankara University TechnoCity, Turkey

- Scripted a database migration interface to move bug reports to a new program using SQL and C#.
- Experienced with WCF Web Services, ASP.Net, C#, JQuery, MSSQL, and PL/SQL.

IT Support Engineer Sep 2011-Jun 2012

Kirikkale University Library, Computer Support Specialist, Turkey

(1-Year Part-time)

- * Maintained and supported of library computers.
- ❖ Provided IT support to library employee and prepared IT training materials.

EDUCATION:

M.A.Sc. Electrical & Computer Engineering, University of Ottawa, Canada (Full Scholarship)

Sep 2015-Jun 2018

- ♦ Developed deep learning models for semantic image segmentation for 34 3D LGE-MR images using Python, Matlab and C++.
- Thesis title: Image Processing Methods for Myocardial Scar Analysis from 3D Late-Gadolinium Enhanced Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Images.

B.Sc. Computer Engineering, Kirikkale University, Turkey

Sep 2009-Jun 2013

- Completed courses; Artificial Intelligence, Image Processing, Advanced Data Structures, Algorithm Design, Object Oriented Programming, Databases, and Web Development.
- Excelled at scripting with C, C++ and C# for many desktop applications and database systems.

PUBLICATIONS:

- F. Usta, W. Gueaieb, J. A. White, C. McKeen, and E. Ukwatta, "Comparison of myocardial scar geometries generated
- from 2D and 3D LGE MRI," p. 19, Mar. 2018, SPIE Medical Imaging, Houston, TX.
 F. Usta, W. Gueaieb, J. A. White, and E. Ukwatta, "3D scar segmentation from LGE-MRI using a continuous maxflow method," p. 29, Mar. 2018, SPIE Medical Imaging, Houston, TX.

SKILLS:

Deep Learning and Image Analysis

- Solid machine learning and medical image analysis background with Python and Matlab.
- Python, PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Matlab, C++, numpy and scikit-image, h5py/HDF5 and CUDA cudnn
- Dicom, Nifty, Meta Images, and binary files

Manual Image Annotating:

- Highly experienced with manual scar segmentation and myocardium registration from over 35 3D images.
- * Excellent understanding of calcified plaque detection on 3D CCTA images of over 600 patients.

Academic Writing

- ❖ Academic English, IELTS Academic 7.5/9, Academic Writing.
- LaTex for technical paper writing.

Other Proficiency

- Certificated Cisco CCNA Discovery Network Administrator, 120 hour in-class training in 2012.
- Git, Github and bitBucket
- Advanced Data Structures, Algorithm Design

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITY:

 Guest Lecturer for Engineering Mini Courses Program (EMCP). Taught in an image processing May 2017 course to over 20 grade-8 students, Carleton University, On, Canada.

❖ 3Minute Thesis Competition, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada. Video Link. April 2017

❖ 2nd Place, Robotic Challenge, Bilkent University Robotic Days, Ankara, Turkey. May 2010

I love being active and biking. I have amateur drawings.